- [Narrator] This is Fox 45 Morning News.
- Well up next we have
a workout plan that's so
automatic it works like
a computer program.
We have expert advice
on getting your routine
down to a T.
Well here to stress the
benefits of an automated
workout routine, we have CEO
of Fit To Go Personal Training,
Dani Singer, so good morning to you,
you've got quite the set
up here in our studio.
- We're gonna have fun today, so--
- What is an automated workout routine?
- The idea is that you
want to make your morning
fitness routine, or whatever
your fitness routine is,
you want to make it automatic, right?
That's something we've talked about a lot.
But, the idea is that when
you're first initiating
your fitness plan, your
routine, you have to
take some willpower.
Take some conscious effort.
But eventually you want
to get to the point
that there's no willpower--
- Not even thinking about it.
- Exactly, there's no decisions
even being made in the moment.
So what we're gonna do today,
is I'm gonna walk through
what a sample morning fitness
routine might be like.
Or just a routine in
general with fitness kind of
automatically in there, without
any thoughts in the moment.
- Okay.
- Ready to do this?
- I'm gonna let you take over.
- All right, so, you start
off, you're down on the ground,
you're sleeping right?
The alarm goes off, you're dreading it,
but now you're not dreading
it because you know
you have a routine set up.
So you get up, you go, you go right away,
first thing you do, as
soon as you get up, you
brush your teeth, done.
Okay, that's automatic,
most people are brushing
their teeth first thing
in the morning anyways.
But then you've anchored
it, so as soon you finish
brushing your teeth,
your brain knows next up,
I get in my workout clothes.
And my workout clothes
are already laid out
from the night before, so
you throw that on right away.
- I like that, I've heard of
some people sleeping in them.
I could never do that.
- I wanted to breakaway pants
that I could just rip off.
Then, bam, you go right to your workout.
And your workouts already
preplanned, you already
know exactly what you're doing.
So you're going into your
workout, maybe 10, 20 minutes,
whatever it is, you get that done.
Automatic, next, bam,
you go into the shower,
you clean up, you smell
great, you throw on some
cologne, now this we gave
its own station right here
with the protein shake,
because this is so key.
- Okay, this is important.
- Something like this, what's
it take, like 30 seconds
to a minute to blend your protein shake?
Blend it the night before,
because that little bit
of time may be the
difference between whether or
not you have time to actually make it.
But if it's ready in your
fridge, you can grab and go.
- Okay, what do you like to do for yours?
- For the protein shake?
- Yeah.
- Just a scoop of whey, I put
a little casein in mine too.
But really any protein shake
that's just high in protein
lower in sugar, will be
a good protein shake.
- Okay, and you've got it on the go,
so you can also keep moving.
- Exactly, and then, once
you've finished that up.
You've already hit your fitness
routine for the day right?
That's already done, so now
it's just time to get ready
and look awesome because
you've already got your workout
in, you smell great, and
you're ready to go and head off
to work.
So then you've got all dressed--
- Doing out little dance here.
- Looking good, and bam,
you're starting your work day.
You got your coffee.
- You don't have to worry
about fitting it in.
- You're ready to go.
- So what is a good length of time,
I'm sure this is gonna take
awhile to become a habit
to fit this all in.
How long are you saying
workouts should be here?
- So, the workout that we
give a lot of our clients
is called "The P.A.U.L.
Method", which literally takes
10 minutes, it's just a body workout.
You can get that on our website for free.
But the idea is that, figure
out what works for you.
However much time you have,
even if its 10 minutes,
you're gonna see a lot
of benefit from there.
But more important than anything
else is make it automatic,
make it a routine, remember
what we went through, right?
My cue was the second I
finish brushing my teeth,
I put on my workout clothes.
Second I finish putting
on my workout clothes,
I start my workout.
So it's automatic,
there's no decision moment
do I workout or not.
It just happens.
- Are you doing this five days a week,
or when's your off day?
- So it depends, if you
do a 10 minute workout
you might want to do it every single day.
If you're doing something
a little more intense,
they might want to take some off days.
But whatever it is, it should
be consistent and automatic.
- [Shelly] And you're not
even saying people have to go
to the gym, and do all of this.
You can work out in your
home, like that's what we
even said, put on a quick home workout.
- [Dani] Exactly, yeah, I
mean yeah that's what we're
all about, we're fitness
for busy professionals
at Fit2Go, so we do in-home training.
We train our clients at
home but more importantly
we teach them to work
out on their own in home
in between sessions.
Because we want them to
build those habits that'll
last long term.
- [Shelly] Okay, and people want to
get in touch do you learn more.
- Fit2GoPT.com, I'm Dani Singer, Fit2Go
and we'll talk to you then.
- All right, thank you very much Dani.